ALEX KIRKUP

SQL/VBA/Excel Developer

About

Email: alex.kirkup@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-kirkup **GitHub**: https://alex-kirkup.github.io/portfolio-sql/

Medium: https://medium.com/@alex.kirkup

I have had 17 years' VBA, Excel and SQL experience building dashboards, developing software solutions and performing statistical analysis. I am presently Lead Data Analyst and Mathematics Teacher at a thriving secondary school, and in this role I have had experience of creating and delivering training and significantly improving the use of data for a team of over 70., and am looking to move into a full-time role in SQL/VBA/Excel development.

Skills

VBA/Excel SQL Python Statistics Training SQL Server Dashboards Django / FastAPI Analysis Communication MySQL Visualisations Pandas Modelling Teaching PostgreSQL PivotTables NumPy Research Online delivery Matplotlib PowerQuery AGILE / Git / Pylint

Relevant Experience

Lead Data Analyst, Cams Hill School, 06/2019-present

- Created and implemented a new whole school approach to working with pupil data by using PostgreSQL, VBA and Excel to move data usage away from a basic management information system by creating new dashboards, visualisations, modelling and data collection processes.
- Modelled GCSE grades assigned to pupils based on individual, school and national past attainment during Covid disruption to exams.

Pupil Premium Coordinator, Cams Hill School, 06/2017-06/2019

Teacher of Mathematics, Cams Hill School, 09/2015-present

- Introduced a new system of individualised pupil feedback in mathematics by using PostgreSQL, VBA and Excel which has changed the culture of learning for pupils and improved outcomes, created new positive links between home and school, and increased teachers' capacity to plan effectively.
- Created the Mixed Question Worksheet Generator using VBA and Excel based on a bank of 10,000 pre-made questions to match the department's teaching to the latest education research.

Teacher of Mathematics, The Hayling College, 09/2013-08/2015

Research Fellow, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Sheffield, 09/2010-08/2012

University Lecturer, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Sheffield, 09/2009-08/2010

Teaching Fellow, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Southampton, 09/2008-08/2009

References

Mrs Gwennan Harrison-Jones Executive Headteacher Cams Hill School Fareham Hampshire, PO15 6NL office@camshill.com Mr Charles Fairhead Head of Mathematics Cams Hill School Fareham Hampshire, PO15 6NL office@camshill.com

Education

Software Engineering Bootcampt

HyperionDev, 12/2022-03/2023

PGCE Secondary Education

University of Portsmouth, 2012-2013

PhD Global Political Economy

(Including MPhil Statistical and Research Methods)

University of Southampton, 2005-2009

MSc Global Politics

University of Southampton, 2004-2005

BSc (Hons) Economics and Politics

University of Southampton, 2001-2004

A-Levels Mathematics, Further Mathematics (AS), Computing, Business Studies

Fareham College, 1999-2001

My Medium blog posts

Making error messages visible in Django forms

The "ManagementForm data is missing or has been tampered with" error in Django

Creating dynamic labels for Django form fields

Access an item in a list using Django Template Language by writing a Custom

When whole school data works for everyone

Making the most of pupil data